# Sahil Johari

Pittsburgh PA 15219 | 214-458-7161 | sahiljohari12@gmail.com | LinkedIn | GitHub

# **Summary of Qualifications**

Offering **2.5 years of experience** in software engineering. Currently **working as a Front-end Software Engineer** in agile environment and creating some exciting and rewarding user interfaces for web apps using modern frameworks.

- Key Competencies -

Communication | Problem solving | Teamwork | Creativity | Passion | Quick Learning | Curiosity | Ownership

# **Technical Skills**

- HTML, CSS/SASS, JavaScript, React, Redux, Node, TypeScript
- Cypress, Jest, Enzyme, RSpec-rails
- Python, MySQL
- REST API consumption, Git/GitHub

# **Professional Experience**

# Software Engineer - Rivers Agile | IBM - Pittsburgh, PA

August 2019 – Present

- Work on the front-end portion of *Discovery Tooling* an online tool in IBM Watson™ Discovery, with 35 user stories completed so far
- Collaborate with other developers from front-end, back-end, and UI/UX designers to create product features
- Successfully completed and deployed over 18 user stories/features for product release in November 2019
- Developed and owned the conversational feature (**Chat Bot**) which uses Discovery API to provide intuitive responses to user queries
- Contributed significantly in migrating over 30 integration tests from *rspec-rails* to *Cypress* framework to improve testability, maintainability, and code readability

# Senior Analyst - Capgemini Technology Services India Limited - India

June 2015 – June 2017

- Reduced the lead time by 80% (as reported) for the customer via generating and distributing over 125 reports by developing an automation web application using .NET framework
- Enhanced the user experience by migrating legacy front-end code to newer technologies such as jQuery and Bootstrap
- Independently analyzed and validated program specifications as well as developed reliable and reusable C# code

# **Education**

#### Master of Science, Computer Science

Southern Methodist University, Dallas, Texas

**Bachelor of Engineering, Information Technology** 

University of Mumbai, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India

# May 2019

GPA: 3.53/4.0

# June 2015

**GPA: 70.13% (Final Year)** 

# **Additional Experience**

#### **Graduate Teaching Assistant**

January 2019 - April 2019

Department of Computer Science and Engineering, Southern Methodist University - Dallas, Texas

- Course: Principles of Computer Science
- Instructed undergraduate students on hands-on programming sessions in *Java* conducted for a span of 8 weeks

# **Projects**

# **Game for Intelligent Simulated Military Opponents (Academic)**

**August 2018 – December 2018** 

Simulated a battlefield via neuro-evolution in which two rival forces compete to win using "firing tanks" without any human aid. *JavaScript, TensorFlow.js, p5.js* 

# Playing Snake using Deep Reinforcement Learning (Academic)

June 2018 - August 2018

Achieved game score of 7 on a 10x10 board using a Deep Q-learning Neural Network. Python, TensorFlow, Keras